Guide to the Richard C. Carroll, Assistant and Associate Dean of Yale College, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records of Richard C. Carroll, Circa 1937-1961; Accession 1996-A-020
  - Grades statistics, Spring 1951 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Grade Distribution and Statistics, Spring 1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Grade Distribution Yale College, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Graduate Study Abroad Fellowships, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Guba, Phil correspondence to Dean Carroll, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Harvard Club of Cleveland, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Harvard V-12 transfers, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Headquarters Army Training School, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Heeling procedure changes, November 28, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Henry Fellowships, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - History department critique, April 1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - (The) Honor Code, Yes or No?, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Honors Committee suggestions, definition of standards, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hotchkiss graduates statistics, 1940-1952 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Hotchkiss graduates in Yale College summary (classes of 1957, 1958, 1959), December 1, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - (The) Honor System in Higher Education, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - (The) Humanities and the Student, February 22, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "The Impact of War on the Liberal Arts College," written by Carroll, Richard C.; Yale College, September 22, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Impressions of Yale, May 21, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - (Yale College) Information blanks, October 29, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Instruction of soldiers and apprentice seamen, April 27, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Intensive and standard majors estimate, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Interview notes with Dean Dell, Burnham; April 17, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Jurisdiction proposals between the schools, departments, and colleges, Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Language class registration, January 12, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Law School recommendations, Yale, August 18, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Liberal Arts correspondence, December 9, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "The Liberal Education", October 31, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Liberal education experiment, Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Loans and scholarships, 1934-1971 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Major Elections Averages, 1930-1942 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Major election trends in Yale College (1930-1942), 1902-1948 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Major selections of the class of 1950, November 1948 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Major selections summary, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Major subjects election trends, 1930-1948 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Majors in Yale College (1942-1943), May 4, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Marks and averages, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Masters Thesis correspondence, September 2, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Matrimonial permission correspondence, March 17, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Maturity Through Student Counseling, November 28, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Medical schools, acceptance statistics, Undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Important and approved) Medical schools in the United States, Undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Meeting correspondence, October 29, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Meeting minutes of small Executive Committee of Yale College, May 1956 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Meeting minutes of the Executive Committee of Yale College, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Meeting minutes of the Deans' Committee, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Meeting minutes, Yale Committees, June 03, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Memorandum on Acceleration, Undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Military service, January 1956 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Military service pamphlet and correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Miniature Tree Growers' Association, Transactions of the, February 1947 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - (Proposal for temporary) N.R.O.T.C. major leading to a Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) degree, August 3, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - (The) Nature and Aims of General Education, Undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Naval reading course outline, July 21, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Naval training academic credit correspondence, August 19, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Navy V-12 pamphlets, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Needs and Plans for Yale College proposal, July 17, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Negatives, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - (The) New England Social Studies bulletin, December 1950 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - New Method for Elections to Senior Societies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - News clippings and correspondence (1938, 1940, 1941), 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - New Haven at Work broadcast, January 19, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Notes by Dean DeVane, Undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Notes on Harvard College: graphic and statistical, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Office assignments, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Office procedure, September 15, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - The Old Blue Tomb tote sheet, April 8, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - On Defending Private Property, written by Carey, Jeffrey T., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - On the Right Track, November 16, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Operation of a Navy V-12 unit manual, June 18, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Opportunities for postgraduate study and employment and for summer study abroad, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Outline of Testing programs, July 1943 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Passport request: Carroll, Richard Cushman, June 19, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - (The) Performance of Progressive School students, August 6, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Phi Beta Kappa men in Yale, 1930-1949 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Phillips Andover Academy graduates summary (classes of 1957, 1958, and 1959), September 1956 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Physical Education department data, August 8, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Points for Preceptors, Princeton University, September 1953 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Possible advisors for divisional programs, Undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Post Graduate study or Employment Opportunities, September 1954 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Post War Program, memorandum regarding extra-curricular activities, Undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - (Yale's) Post-war social system, January 11, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Post-war student activities, Council Committee on, May 8, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Post-war Yale discussion questions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Pre-induction Scholarship revised proposal for 1952 program, November 20, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Pre-Medical candidates, 1937-1943 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Pre-Medical Men, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Pre-Medical students statistics, Circa. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Prep School Athletic Experience, October 7, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - President's Committee report on the teaching of modern foreign languages, May 15, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Program announcement and schedule, September 16, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Proposed Pre-Medical course, 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Psychiatry and Mental Hygiene department, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Quota statistics for the Sophomore applicants of the Army Enlisted Reserve Corps., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Rating scale for teachers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Readmission correspondence, February 12, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Readmission correspondence, February 15, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Readmission statistics, September 26, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Reasons for failures class of 1940, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Recorded behavior of the classes of 1950 and 1951, October 9, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Registration statistics, Undated (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Regulations of Yale College, September 13, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Religion and post-war life at Yale, Undated (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Report of Committee on Round Table Groups, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Reports of The President's Committee on General Education, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Reports and Materials, August 1940 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Report for the Executive Committee meeting, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Resignations because of health, November 12, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Retrospect and Prospect; A Special Report on the Twenty-Fifth Anniversary of the Student Mental Hygiene Service at Yale, June 1951 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Revised minimum requirements applications, 1939-1942 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Revised minimum requirements applied to the class of 1941 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Revisions of University calendar during war time memorandum, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation - A Review for 1943 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - The Rough Passage, an address at Western Reserve Academy, May 28, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Rules and suggestions governing fraternity activities, September 29, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Ruskin's Inaugural Lecture at Oxford, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Saint Elmo news, June 1941 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - The Satisfaction Study: A Progress Report, May 3, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - School and College Study of Admission with Advanced Standing, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - School of Engineering, grade distribution, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Science majors in Yale College survey, December 20, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Second summary of information about the Army-Navy College Training Program, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Selective Service and Veteran Affairs, September 12, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Selective service data, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Self-support and secondary school status, December 7, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Senior election of majors, 1946-1952 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Senior societies proposed schedule of elections, October 29, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Senior societies representatives, April 19, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Senior society elections - class of 1958, May 02, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - Senior society elections summary, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Senior societies, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Senior year problem cases, class of 1940 (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Sociology reading list, Undated (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Sophomore counseling plan, November 13, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Sophomore cuts comparison, May 13, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - (Yale) Standards for personal integrity, Undated (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Statistics for the class of 1945, November 3, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Statistics for the class of 1945, December 3, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - Saint Mark's study, January 12, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Student advancement correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - Student averages, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 156)
  - Student correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 157)
  - Student incompletions, May 9, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 158)
  - Student Life, Yale, 1934-1966 (Box 2, Folder 159)
  - Student life and activities, re: post-war era, Undated (Box 2, Folder 160)
  - Student Mental Hygiene department organization, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 161)
  - Student withdrawals correspondence and statistics, June 24, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 162)
  - Study of transfer students in Yale College, 1932-1940 (Box 2, Folder 163)
  - Summer reading class of 1951 and 1952, May 10, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 164)
  - Summer reading list I, June 1, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 165)
  - Summer reading list, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 166)
  - The Surface and the Substance of Education, convocation address, October 1955 (Box 2, Folder 167)
  - (Fifty-nine year) Survey, December 1941 (Box 2, Folder 168)
  - A survey of language classes in the Army Specialized Training Program (A.S.T.P.), 1944 (Box 2, Folder 169)
  - Survey results, Undated (Box 2, Folder 170)
  - Tentative majors, Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 171)
  - Tokyo correspondence, January 18, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 172)
  - Transfer applicants for admission to Yale, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 174)
  - The Underclass Years, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 175)
  - Educational Program for Members of the Armed Forces during the Period of Demobilization, 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 176)
  - Undergraduate Activities Committee correspondence and policy, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 177)
  - Undergraduate and the Problem of Enlistment, December 23, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 178)
  - Undergraduate enlistment, December 23, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 179)
  - Undergraduate essays, Undated (Box 2, Folder 180)
  - Undergraduate Fellowships correspondence, August 9, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 181)
  - Undergraduate prizes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 182)
  - Undergraduate studies program proposal for returning service men (Yale), July 26, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 183)
  - University Police, February 24, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 184)
  - United States Naval Reserve Policy correspondence, August 15, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 185)
  - The Uses of a Liberal Education, A Convocation Address by Professor of Philosophy, Blanshard, Brand, September 1949 (Box 2, Folder 186)
  - Varsity team participation eligibility, 1947 May 29 (Box 2, Folder 187)
  - Veterans 'Neath the Ivy, by Kone, Eugene H., April 15, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 188)
  - War time pamphlets, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 189)
  - War years at Yale, 1942-1950 (Box 2, Folder 190)
  - Withdrawal correspondence, September 21, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 192)
  - Woodrow Wilson Fellows for the Academic Year 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 193)
  - Woodrow Wilson Fellowship Program, September 1, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 194)
  - World Champion Crew and the Ivy League Football Champions, February 13, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 195)
  - Yale calendar revisions, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 196)
  - Yale College Athletics and Freshman Intramural Athletics, 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 197)
  - Yale College Faculty regulations revisions, June 28, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 198)
  - Yale College Faculty votes, December 12, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 199)
  - Yale College general statistics, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 200)
  - Yale College men who were dropped, demoted, or resigned for scholastic reasons, 1941-1946 (Box 2, Folder 201)
  - Yale College Policy, September 11, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 202)
  - Yale College Reading Courses for Armed Forces, Undated (Box 2, Folder 203)
  - Yale College statistics, Fall term, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 204)
  - Yale College statistics, May 1949 (Box 2, Folder 205)
  - Yale College summary (classes of 1957, 1958, 1959), September 1956 (Box 2, Folder 206)
  - Yale College withdrawals, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 207)
  - Yale Daily News Course Critique, March 1954 (Box 2, Folder 208)
  - Yale Daily News, October 23, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 209)
  - Yale Daily News, March 10, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 210)
  - Yale graduates teaching in secondary schools, 1939-1949 (Box 2, Folder 211)
  - Yale News clippings on Yale Health, January 28, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 212)
  - Yale University News Bureau, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 213)